Guide to the Stanford University, School of Earth Sciences, Records SC0405
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Additional Records, 1893-2005; Accession ARCH_2016_135; Stanford University, School of Earth Sciences Records, SES History. This series contains meeting records, correspondence, speeches, presentations, essays, media (photographs, CDs, DVDs, audio cassettes), and documents related to the activitie
  - Buildings, 1906-1999 (inclusive), 1987-1999 (bulk); Subseries 6
    - Hartley Conference Center Dedication, includes invitation and photographs, 1986 Nov 17 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - School and Departmental Events and Field Trips, 1947-1999 (inclusive); Subseries 7
    Documents and photographs of School of Earth Sciences events and field fields from 1947 to 1999. Includes itineraries, invitations, flyers, news clippings.
    - Field Trips - George McLeod, 1947-1948 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Petroleum Engineering Department, 1958-1999 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Petroleum Engineering Field Trips Photos (1 of 2), 1979, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Petroleum Engineering Field Trips Photos (2 of 2), 1984, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Field Trip to Israel and Jordan - Amos Nur, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Earth Systems Program, 1992-2000 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - USGS Fieldwork, 1953-1991 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - USGS Photographs (1 of 2), 1984-1991 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - USGS Photographs (2 of 2), circa 1983-2000 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - USGS Fellows Dinner Photographs (1 of 2), 1994 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - USGS Fellows Dinner Photographs (2 of 2), 1994 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - USGS Barbecue Photographs, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - USGS SHRIMP Dedication, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Senior Alumni Day, 1985, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Alumni Day, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - George Thompson Celebration, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Unocal Centennial Barbecue, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Unocal Centennial Barbecue, 1991, 1993, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Centennial, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Centennial Honor Roll, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Unocal Barbecue Photographs (1 of 4), 1991 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Unocal Barbecue Photographs (2 of 4), 1993 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Unocal Barbecue Photographs (3 of 4), 1993 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Unocal Barbecue Photographs (4 of 4), 1993 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Unocal Barbecue Photographs (Roll 1 of 3) Alumni reunion, third Unocal Barbecue, Green Bldg, Kresge Plaza, photos by Mike Diggles, 1997 Sep 26 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Unocal Barbecue Photographs (Roll 2 of 3) Alumni reunion, third Unocal Barbecue, Green Bldg, Kresge Plaza, photos by Mi, 1997 Sep 26 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Unocal Barbecue Photographs (Roll 3 of 3) Alumni reunion, third Unocal Barbecue, Green Bldg, Kresge Plaza, photos by Mi, 1997 Sep 26 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Green Shanty Dinner, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Green Shanty Dinner, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Alumni Day, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Reunion/BAJA Barbecue (1 of 3), 1994 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Reunion/BAJA Barbecue (2 of 3), 1994 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Reunion/BAJA Barbecue (1 of 3), 1994 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Reunion Weekend, 1994-1995 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Alumni Day/Reunion Weekend, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Stanford in Washington Dinner - Alumni Day, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - GSA Reunion - Denver, 1994, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Frank West Dinner, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Mack Family Luncheon Photographs - Roll A, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Mack Family Luncheon Photographs - Roll B, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Mack Family Luncheon Photographs (1 of 2), 1998 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Mack Family Luncheon Photographs (2 of 2), 1998 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Faculty and Students Photographs, 1919-1992 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Geology and Earth Sciences Students, 1950s-1998 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Geology and Earth Sciences Field Trips, circa 1990-1998 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Geology and Earth Sciences Events, 1990-1999 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Women in Earth Sciences, 1964-1997 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Group Events, 1987-1999 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Volunteers - Photographs, 1990-1991 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Computers in the Mineral Industries program, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - School of Mineral Sciences Newsletter, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Commencement, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Commencement, 1991-1992 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Commencement, 1993-1999 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Publications, 1952-2003 (inclusive); Subseries 8
    Publications associated with the School of Earth Sciences. Includes school and departmental publications, student publications, and publications featuring earth scientists. Contains original publications and related documents. The following publications were removed from the collection and added to the Branner Library collection or disposed as duplicate publications: Geohistory Newsletters (1980, 1987 and 1991), Uncle Bert. A Biographical Portrait of Herbert Hoover by Helda Hoover McLean (1974), ASESSU Newletters (1996-1999), The Geological and Mining Society of American Universities Yearbooks (1914-1915, 1917, 1921-1922, and 1942), and Stanford Earth Scientists (1958, 1962, 1968, 1974, 1980, 1985 and 1990).
    - Directory of Stanford Mineral Scientists, circa 1952-1983 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Directory of Stanford Mineral Scientists, 1982-1983 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Student Spoof Newspaper, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Earth Scientists in Publications, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Earth Scientists in Publications – Sandstone and Tile, 1985, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Earth Scientists in Publications: AAPG Explorer, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - The Stanford Centennial Campaign, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - The Art of the Friday Beer, 1988-1993 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Friday Beer Posters, circa 1988-1993 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Friday Beer Posters, circa 1990s (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Publications Order Form, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Time Slices, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Stanford Earth Sciences Report, 2001-2003 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - ESC Slide Presentations, 1893-1999 (inclusive); Subseries 9
    Slides organized for presentations detailing the history of the School of Earth Sciences department and the field, school’s buildings field trips, faculty, and projects.
    - General Campus and Environs, SLAC and Synchotron, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Geology Corner and Green Building, 1996-1997 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - SHRIMP, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Mitchell Building, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Mining the Past: A Rich History in Photographs, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Commencement, 1986, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Faculty, 1962-1999 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Fossil Faculty, circa 1920-1997 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Stanford Geological Survey, 1893-1997 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Death Valley Trips, 1996-1997 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Team Projects - Wagon Rock/China, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Alumni, 1895-1994 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Maps, circa 1975-1998 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Monterey Bay Aquarium Research Institute (MBARI), 1994-1997 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Lynn Orr’s Planes, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - People, Equipment, and Labs, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - ESC Slides Title Slides, circa 1997 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Negatives and Proof Sheets, 1893-2001 (inclusive); Subseries 10
    All negatives, large format and 35 mm, and proof sheets that are associated with the collection. Indices are included in folders.
    - Large format negatives (1 of 3) (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Large format negatives (2 of 3) (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Large format negatives (3 of 3) (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - 35mm negatives (1 of 2), undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - 35mm negatives (2 of 2), undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Matched Negatives and Proofs (1 of 3), undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Matched Negatives and Proofs (2 of 3), undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Matched Negatives and Proofs (3 of 3), undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Proofs (1 of 3), undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Proofs (2 of 3), undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Proofs (3 of 3) (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Green Building Negatives and Proofs, 1991, 1993, 2001 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Petroleum Engineering Department, 1954, circa 1958 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Unocal Centennial Barbecue Negatives and Proofs, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Unocal Barbecue Negatives for rolls 1-3, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 15)